Abhishek Singh

Experienced working professionally as a Data Analyst trainer having more than three months of experience. Highly interested in Machine learning and deep learning algorithms who's looking forward to working as a Machine learning Engineer

Varanasi , India +919997700487 a.singh.gla@gmail.com <u>Linkedin</u> <u>Github</u>

EXPERIENCE

DCS, India — [L2 Data Analyst]

Jun 2023 - Feb 2024

- In DCS I mainly work as a trainer who gave training of data analytics and machine learning
- Here I have worked on the Smart EV project where I have to take sensor data from thingworx then doing the data analysis on that data

Ineuron [internship]

Dec 2023 - Jan 2024

- Created the web app by which we can easily understood that which parameter is more important for the high or low rating of the restaurant ,taking insights for data analysis, unveiling correlations between various factors and customer satisfaction
- Apply regression analysis to optimize models, integrate relevant features, and contribute to accurate rating forecasts and uses CI/CD pipeline for the deployment
- Tools used: Python, sklearn library, EDA, MongoDB

SKILLS

Hard Skills:

- Data Analysis (intermediate)
- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- MLOPS
- LLM
- SQL
- Modeling
- Data Visualization

Techniques:

- Predictive Analytics
- Clustering
- Natural Language Processing

Tools:

- PowerBl
- TensorFlow
- Flask
- Python

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Brain Tumor Prediction (Deep Learning)

- Here we have to predict the MRI images of brain that have tumor or not
- Spearhead advancements in medical imaging using Deep Learning, specifically Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs), with expertise in pooling, padding.
- Tools used: Python, CNN ,batch normalization, optimizers (Adam) and activation function (Relu)

Sales analysis (PowerBI)

 Created the sales dashboard using powerBI in that i have different different chart for the better visualization

Generative AI (Gemini AI)

- Created LLM Application in which it can able to answer your query as the Chat gpt model can do
- Created LLM application which can able to extract information from the images so that it can tell you about the information that you want from that image

EDUCATION

B Tech - Computer Science

D. Tech - Computer science	[/./]
GLA University, Mathura	[2019 - 2023]
High School	[9.4]
[Kendriya Vidhyalaya]	[2015 - 2016]
Intermediate	[9.4]
[Kendriya Vidhyalaya]	[2018 - 2019]

[77]

CERTIFICATE (Data Science & Data Analytics)

- Ineuron
- Simplilearn
- Ekeeda
- techTip 24